Inventory of the NSZZ "Solidarność" (Labor organization) Records
Hoover Institution Archives
NSZZ "Solidarność" (Labor organization) records
1980-1991
92025
Hoover Institution Archives
530 phonotape cassettes in 14 oversize boxes (10.5 linear feet)
Sound recording copies of plenary sessions and sessions of the presidium of the Komisja Krajowa, plenary sessions of the Krajowy Zjazd Delegatów, sessions of various regional congresses and local branches, sessions of various workers' self-management committees, and negotiation sessions with government representatives. The recordings relate to labor, economic and political conditions in Poland.
NSZZ "Solidarność" (Labor organization)
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. Use copies of some sound recordings, video recordings, or motion picture material in this collection are available for immediate access. To listen to other sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1992.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Location of Originals
Originals in: Archiwum Solidarnośći, Warsaw.
Historical Note
Polish trade union and political movement.
Scope and Content of Collection
Sound recording copies of plenary sessions and sessions of the presidium of the Komisja Krajowa, plenary sessions of the Krajowy Zjazd Delegatów, sessions of various regional congresses and local branches, sessions of various workers' self-management committees, and negotiation sessions with government representatives. The recordings relate to labor, economic and political conditions in Poland.
Labor movement--Poland.; Labor unions--Poland.; Phonotapes.; Poland--Economic conditions--1981-1990.; Poland--Politics and government--1980-1989.
- Sound recordings of Krajowa Komisja Porozumiewawcza/Komisja Krajowa (KKP/KK) plenary sessions, 1980-1981; 96 compact sound cassettes (Box 1)
  - Sound recordings of Krajowa Komisja Porozumiewawcza (KKP -- National Coordinating Commission) plenary sessions, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
    - 1980 (Box 1)
      - 17 September, version 1 (Box 1)
        General note
        The audio of cassettes 1 in versions 1 and 2 do not sync. Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0007459
      - 17 September, version 2 (Box 1)
        The audio of cassettes 1 in versions 1 and 2 do not sync. Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0007468
      - 22 September (Box 1)
        Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0007442
      - 6 October (Box 1)
        Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0007443
      - 31 October (Box 1)
        Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0007458
      - 9 November (Box 1)
        Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0007453
      - 10 November, Supreme Court (Box 1)
        Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0007457
      - 19 November (Box 1)
        Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0007461
      - 26 November, 4 compact sound cassettes (Box 1)
        Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0007462
      - December, plenary session of "11" (eleven biggest regions) (Box 1)
        Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0007460
    - 1981
      - Bydgoszcz (Box 1)
        Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008051
      - 28-29 January (Box 1)
        Access
        Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0006691
      - 1 February (KP -- Program Committee) (Box 1)
        Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0006701
      - 25 February (Box 1-2)
        Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008054
      - 31 March - 1 April (Box 2)
        Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0007792
      - 9-10 April (Box 2)
        Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008055
      - 4 June (Box 2)
        Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0007213
      - July (Box 2)
        Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0007208
      - August (Box 2)
        Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0007762
  - Sound recordings of Komisja Krajowa (KK -- National Commission) plenary sessions, 1981 (Box 2)
    - 22-23 October, 1 compact sound cassette (Box 2)
      Only tape 9 exists. Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008060
    - 3-4 November (Box 2-3)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0007166
    - 11-12 December (Box 3)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0006730
    - 11 December, supplement, 1 compact sound cassette (Box 3)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008061
  - Sound recordings of Komisja Krajowa (KK) Presidium sessions, Radom, 2 December (Box 3)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008062
- Sound recordings of I Krajowy Zjazd Delegatów (IKZD -- 1st National Convention of Delegates) meetings, 1981; 118 compact sound cassettes (Box 3)
  - General (Box 3-6)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Cassette 001: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008063
    Cassette 002: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008064
    Cassette 003: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008065
    Cassette 004: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008066
    Cassette 005: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008070
    Cassette 006: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008071
    Cassette 007: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008072
    Cassette 008: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008073
    Cassette 009: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008076
    Cassette 010: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008077
    Cassette 011: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008080
    Cassette 012: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008081
    Cassette 013: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008083
    Cassette 014: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008084
    Cassette 015: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008085
    Cassette 016: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008086
    Cassette 017: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008087
    Cassette 018: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008088
    Cassette 019: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008089
    Cassette 020: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008090
    Cassette 021: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008091
    Cassette 022: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008092
    Cassette 023: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008094
    Cassette 024: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008095
    Cassette 025: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008098
    Cassette 026: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008099
    Cassette 027: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008100
    Cassette 028: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008101
    Cassette 029: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008102
    Cassette 030: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008103
    Cassette 031: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008105
    Cassette 032: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008106
    Cassette 033: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008108
    Cassette 034: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008109
    Cassette 035: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008111
    Cassette 036: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008112
    Cassette 037: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008118
    Cassette 038: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008119
    Cassette 039: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008124
    Cassette 040: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008125
    Cassette 041: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008131
    Cassette 042: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008132
    Cassette 043: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008137
    Cassette 044: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008138
    Cassette 045: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008140
    Cassette 046: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008141
    Cassette 047: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008144
    Cassette 048: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008145
    Cassette 049: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008146
    Cassette 050: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008147
    Cassette 051: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008148
    Cassette 052: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008149
    Cassette 053: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008150
    Cassette 054: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008151
    Cassette 055: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008155
    Cassette 056: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008156
    Cassette 057: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008160
    Cassette 058: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008161
    Cassette 059: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008166
    Cassette 060: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008167
    Cassette 061: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008168
    Cassette 062: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008169
    Cassette 063: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008173
    Cassette 064: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008174
    Cassette 065: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008177
    Cassette 066: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008178
    Cassette 067: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008181
    Cassette 068: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008182
    Cassette 069: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008386
    Cassette 070: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008387
    Cassette 071: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008390
    Cassette 072: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008391
    Cassette 073: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008395
    Cassette 074: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008396
    Cassette 075: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008401
    Cassette 076: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008402
    Cassette 077: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008405
    Cassette 078: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008406
    Cassette 079: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008409
    Cassette 080: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008410
    Cassette 081: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008413
    Cassette 082: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008414
    Cassette 083: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008416
    Cassette 084: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008417
    Cassette 085: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008418
    Cassette 086: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008419
    Cassette 087: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008420
    Cassette 088: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008421
    Cassette 089: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008436
    Cassette 090: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008437
    Cassette 091: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008508
    Cassette 092: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008509
    Cassette 093: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008513
    Cassette 094: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008514
    Cassette 095: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008515
    Cassette 096: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008516
    Cassette 097: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008520
    Cassette 098: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008521
    Cassette 099: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008522
    Cassette 100: Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008523
  - Małopolska region delegates meeting (Box 6)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008527
  - Primaries, Mazowsze region (Box 6)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008528
  - Program Committee (Box 6)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0006687
  - Program Committee - "Solidarity and Other Social Movements" (Box 6)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0007742
- Sound recordings of Regional Self-Governed Workers' Unions sessions, 1981; 138 compact sound cassettes (Box 6)
  - Sound recordings of Sieć Organizacji Zakładowych NSZZ Solidarność (Leading Enterprises' Unions Network) plenary sessions, 1981 (Box 6)
    - Kraków, 11-13 May (Box 6)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008531
    - Poznañ, 2 June (Box 6)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008532
    - Katowice, 23-24 June (Box 6)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0007201
    - Warszawa, 26 June (Box 6)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0010494
    - Gdañsk, 8 July (Box 7)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008602
    - Bygdoszcz, 28-30 July (Box 7)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008605
    - Rzeszów, 12-15 August (Box 7)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008612
    - Supraśl-Fasty, 10-13 November (Box 7)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008621
    - świętochłowice, 8-10 December (Box 7)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008628
  - Sound recordings of congresses and sessions of self-governed labor unions' representatives, 1981 (Box 7)
    - Walny Zjazd Delegatów (General Convention of Delegates), 1981 (Box 7)
      - Dolny śl¹sk Region (Box 7)
        Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008629
      - Małopolska Region (Box 7)
        Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008633
      - Mazowsze Region (Box 8)
        Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008738
  - Sound recordings of meetings and plenary sessions of self-governed unions and management, 1981 (Box 8)
    - Gdañsk Region, 9 April - 5 August (Box 8-9)
      Use copy reference numbers: 92025_a_0008754: 15 - 17 April 92025_a_0008859: 29 April 92025_a_0008864: 06 May 92025_a_0008855: 17 June 92025_a_0008865: ?? June 92025_a_0008990:13 July 92025_a_0008869: 20 July 92025_a_0008872: 05 August 92025_a_0008991: undated
    - Mazowsze Region, July 1981 (Box 9)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009014
    - Mazowsze Region, July 1981, October 1981 (Box 10)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009025
    - Warsaw University of Technology, 7 August 1981 (Box 10)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009027
    - Lublin, July 1981 (Box 10)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009028
    - Międzyzakładowy Komitet Zało¿ycielski (MKZ -- Interfactory Founding Committee) meetings, 1980
      - MKZ Mazowsze, 20 September 1980 (Box 10)
        Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009033
        Scope and Contents note
        KIK - 20.IX.80v I ZEBRANIE PRZEDSTAWICIEU KOMITETOW ZALOZYAELSKICH
      - MKZ Olsztyn, November 1980 (Box 10)
        Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009037
- Sound recordings of conflicts and strikes, 1980-1981; 81 compact sound cassettes (Box 10)
  - Gdañsk Shipyard, 16 August 1980 (Box 10)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009056
  - Railway, 1980 (Box 10)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009057
  - Autumn, 1980 (Box 10)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009060
  - Health Service, November 1980; There are three copies of the Health Service recordings. The first is 3 cassettes long. The second is 2 cassettes long. The third is 3 cassettes long. (Box 10-11)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009150
  - Częstochowa, November 1980 (Box 11)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009157
  - Bielsko-Biała, 1981 (Box 11)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0005490
  - Jelenia Góra, 8 February 1981 (Box 11)
    The sound quality is often poor on the accessioned cassettes and, thus, on the digital files.
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009164
  - Ursus, "Naro¿niak Case", 27 November 1981 (Box 11)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009169
  - Lubogóra, 1981 (Box 11)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009174
  - "świerczewski", 27-31 March 1981 (Box 11)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009180
  - May, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Strikes (Box 11-12)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009184
    - Negotiations with the management, August - 19 November 1981 (Box 12)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008423
    - Supplement (Box 12)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009365
- Sound recordings of negotiations with the government authorities, 1981; 22 compact sound cassettes (Box 12)
  - Trade Unions Law, 1981 (Box 12)
    - January (Box 12)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008424
    - 25-26 April (Box 12)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0008425
  - Negotiations with the government, 16-19 October 1981 (Box 12-13)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009385
- Sound recordings of preparations for the Round Table negotiations and elections, 1987-1989; 25 compact sound cassettes (Box 13)
  - Komitet Obywatelski (KO -- Citizens' Committee), 1987-1989 (Box 13)
    - Citizens' Committee with Lech Wałęsa, 7 November 1987 (Box 13)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0007217
    - Citizens' Committee, 23 April 1989 (Box 13)
      Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009487
  - Krajowa Komisja (KK -- National Commission), 5 April 1989, 7 April 1989, 23 April 1989, 29 April 1989, 13 May 1989 (Box 13)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0005500
  - Krajowa Komisja Wyborcza (KKW -- National Electoral Commission), 17 June 1989 (Box 13)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009498
  - Lech Wałęsa's meeting with the candidates for deputies, 29 April 1989 (Box 13)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009504
  - The Social Committee on Economic Reform (Box 13)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009510
- Sound recordings of Krajowy Komitet Obywatelski (KKO -- National Citizens' Committee) meetings, 1990-1991; 34 compact sound cassettes (Box 13)
  - 27 October 1990 (Box 13-14)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009511
  - 1 December 1990 (Box 14)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009522
  - 6 January 1991 (Box 14)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009523
  - 17 February 1991 (Box 14)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009620
  - 14 July 1991 (Box 14)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009621
  - 28 July 1991 (Box 14)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009628
- Miscellaneous sound recordings, 1980-1981; 11 compact sound cassettes (Box 14)
  - Lech Wałęsa, meeting with students in Jastrzębie, 1980 (Box 14)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009629
  - Adam Michnik lecture, December 1980 (Box 14)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009637
  - "Płomienie," discussion about March 1968 events, 1981 (Box 14)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009635
  - Economists on "Prowizorium" (Act of 19 December 1980 on interim budget for 1981), October 1981 (Box 14)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0009638
  - "Kluby Odrodzenia" (Renaissance Clubs), 9 December 1981 (Box 14)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0007761
  - Sound recording R-18, undated (Box 14)
    Use copy reference number: 92025_a_0007848